<blog>
    <article>
        <dateAdded>2023-08-05</dateAdded>
        <html>
            <p>
                Resource packs have been a staple of Minecraft for many years. One slightly less known method of changing Minecraft's look is using shader packs. 
                These shader packs require you to mod your installation, but in return you can alter the visual appearance much more. Instead of changing block
                texture, shader packs generally alter lighting, shadows, clouds, and water effects. So without further ado then, lets go over what shaders and
                resource packs that we use here at Minepaper.
            </p>
            <br />
            <h3>1. Bliss</h3>
            <p>
                The Bliss shader pack is one that give Minecraft a very pastel appearance. Colors are bright and vibrant, but my favorite part are the
                hyperrealistic clouds.
            </p>
            <img src="https://cdn.minepaper.net/2023-08-05_13.20.30.png" class="col-md-6" style="width: 50%; object-fit: contain;"/>
            <br />
            <a href="https://minecraftshader.com/bliss-shaders/" style="color: blue">Download Bliss</a>
            <br />
            <br />
            <h3>2. BSL</h3>
            <p>
                BSL shaders take on a very similar appearance to Bliss in my opinion. The biggest difference to me is the slight aura that appears around blocks
                when the light level is high. Clouds also look much softer than in Bliss, and there is a diamond shaped sun and moon. Shadows and water effects 
                look pretty much the same though.
            </p>
            <img src="https://cdn.minepaper.net/2023-08-05_13.22.48.png" class="col-md-6" style="width: 50%; object-fit: contain;"/>
            <br />
            <a href="https://www.bslshaders.com/download/" style="color: blue">Download BSL</a>
            <br />
            <br />
            <h3>3. ComplementaryReimagined</h3>
            <p>
                This is another shader pack that gives Minecraft a distinct pastel appearance. Unlike in Bliss or BSL however, colors are a tad bit darker. In
                addition, clouds have a funky rounded appearance that makes this pack unique. Lastly, the pastel appearance also appplies to bodies of water
                in this one.
            </p>
            <img src="https://cdn.minepaper.net/2023-08-05_13.25.52.png" class="col-md-6" style="width: 50%; object-fit: contain;"/>
            <br />
            <a href="https://www.complementary.dev/reimagined/" style="color: blue">Download ComplementaryReimagined</a>
            <br />
            <br />
            <h3>4. ProjectLUMA</h3>
            <p>
                ProjectLUMA breaks the pastel trend of the previous items in the list and aims for raw visual fidelity. The colors are highly saturated, 
                shadows are sharp, water looks like it came from a clear mountain stream, and the clouds are ultra realistic. Highly recommended.
            </p>
            <img src="https://cdn.minepaper.net/2023-08-05_13.28.19.png" class="col-md-6" style="width: 50%; object-fit: contain;"/>
            <br />
            <a href="https://minecraftshader.com/projectluma-shaders/" style="color: blue">Download ProjectLUMA</a>
            <br />
            <br />
            <h3>5. Solas Shaders</h3>
            <p>
                This shader pack is the one that I personally find to be the most beautiful. This is mostly owing to the amazing display of stars you will
                see above the clouds even in the daytime. In addition, there is a breathtaking view of the aurora borealis at night that will leave your
                jaws wide open like a barn door. These two factors alone are enough to trick you into thinking you're in a fantasy land, but it doesn't
                end there. The shadows and water effects are perfectly akin to real life, and there is a circular sun and moon to boot. Overall, this is a
                shader pack that is just waiting to wow you, and you should give it a shot if you are looking to spruce up your experience.
            </p>
            <img src="https://cdn.minepaper.net/2023-08-05_13.33.11.png" class="col-md-6" style="width: 50%; object-fit: contain;"/>
            <p>&#xA;</p>
            <img src="https://cdn.minepaper.net/2023-08-05_13.35.48.png" class="col-md-6" style="width: 50%; object-fit: contain;"/>
            <br />
            <a href="https://minecraftshader.com/solas-shaders/" style="color: blue">Download Solas</a>
            <br />
            <br />
            <h3>6. Patrix</h3>
            <p>
                Moving on to resource packs now, we have Patrix. I personally adore Patrix due to the rustic look that it brings to Minecraft. Cobblestone,
                Wood, and Dirt make npc villages look like they come from 16th century Europe. I also enjoy the look of ice blocks in particular, with their
                webbed appearance that makes it look there are air bubbles trapped amongst the frozen blocks.
            </p>
            <img src="https://cdn.minepaper.net/2023-08-05_13.53.08.png" class="col-md-6" style="width: 50%; object-fit: contain;"/>
            <br />
            <a href="https://www.curseforge.com/minecraft/texture-packs/patrix-32x" style="color: blue">Download Patrix</a>
            <br />
            <br />
            <h3>7. ModernArch</h3>
            <p>
                Last but certainly not least, we have ModernArch. This is a resource pack that I find make the look of NPC villages very pleasing in
                particular. Wooden doors have a sleek and modern appearance. Wood and Cobblestone blocks also look very clean, and torches look like old
                school gas lanterns. Overall, I highly recommend this pack if your goal is to spruce up the look of artificial structures in game.
            </p>
            <img src="https://cdn.minepaper.net/2023-08-05_13.54.25.png" class="col-md-6" style="width: 50%; object-fit: contain;"/>
            <br />
            <a href="https://www.designio.graphics/community/downloads/modernarch-1-20-1-19-128x-download" style="color: blue">Download ModernArch</a>
            <br />
            <br />
        </html>
        <description>These are the Shaders and Resource packs that we use when taking screenshots to use as wallpapers</description>
        <category>General</category>
        <title>What Shaders and Resource packs does Minepaper use?</title>
        <author>Timothy Lickteig</author>
        <path>/blog/article/what-shaders-and-resource-packs-does-minepaper-use</path>
        <id>1</id>
        <thumbnailSrc>https://cdn.minepaper.net/2023-08-05_13.35.48.png</thumbnailSrc>
    </article>
    <article>
        <dateAdded>2023-08-05</dateAdded>
        <html>
            <img src="https://www.searchenginejournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/image-search-1600-x-840-px-62c6dc4ff1eee-sej-1280x720.png"></img>
            <p>
                Resource packs have been a staple of Minecraft for many years. One slightly less known method of changing Minecraft's look is using shader packs. 
                These shader packs require you to mod your installation, but in return you can alter the visual appearance much more. Instead of changing block
                texture, shader packs generally alter lighting, shadows, clouds, and water effects. So without further ado then, lets go over what shaders and
                texture packs that we use here at Minepaper.
            </p>
        </html>
        <description>These are the Shaders and Resource packs that we use when taking screenshots to use as wallpapers</description>
        <category>General</category>
        <title>What Shaders and Resource packs does Minepaper use?</title>
        <author>Timothy Lickteig</author>
        <path>/blog/article/what-shaders-and-resource-packs-does-minepaper-use-two</path>
        <id>2</id>
        <thumbnailSrc>https://www.searchenginejournal.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/image-search-1600-x-840-px-62c6dc4ff1eee-sej-1280x720.png</thumbnailSrc>
    </article>
</blog>